Galina Kozyreva

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Summary

Hello, my name is Galina. I am a software engineer with more than a decade of practical experience in developing and maintaining a wide range of software solutions. Some things I am good at and can bring to the team: knowledge of algorithms and architecture, experience as a team leader, experience in a startup environment. I like to think of myself as language-agnostic; however, here's a list of the programming languages I've worked with most often: Python, TypeScript, JavaScript, and C++. I'd be happy to learn something new and open to new challenges. I'm especially drawn to roles that contribute to the environment or have a positive impact on the world.

Education

= 2010 - 2015

Diploma in Computer Science

Saint Petersburg State University of Aerospace and Instrumentation, Faculty of Aerospace Computer and Software Systems

Saint Peterburg, Russia

GPA **1.9**/ 1.0

Contact

+49 176 260 84141

galinka@me.com

% github.io

Work Experience

Full Stack Engineer

Flowplace GmbH

i 2022-Present © Leipzig

- Optimized the frontend UI to improve UX/UI resulting in increased user engagement.
- Led the development at the Flowplace platform, working with Typescript, Vue.js, Nest.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, and Prisma.
- Developed an MVP for new features to gather valuable customer feedback for product enhancements.
- Improved the CI/CD pipeline using Github Actions, and Digital-Ocean, resolving concurrency issues and enhancing the deployment process.
- Ensured GDPR compliance and fortified IT security throughout the software architecture.

Research Assistant

TU Dresden, cfaed – Center for Advancing Electronics Dresden

i 2021-2022 💮 Dresden

 Conducted research on MLIR progressive lowering and advanced optimizations for parallel and emerging computing systems, with a focus on C++.

Senior Software Engineer

Solactive Technologies GmbH

🛱 2020-2021 💮 Dresden

- Developed a data scraping and processing service for government bonds using Python and Flask, with data manipulation handled through Pandas.
- Enhance project architecture win a microservice approach and successfully transitioned it to Kubernetes.

Stack

Front-End:

<u>TypeScript JavaScript React</u>

<u>Redux Vue Canvas</u> (Fabric.js)

Tailwind

Back-End:

Node.js NestJS Python C++
GraphQL Prisma
PostgreSQL Redis

Cloud & Infrastructure:

<u>AWS</u> (Lambda, s3) <u>Heroku</u>

<u>DigitalOcean</u>

Docker Kubernetes Jenkins

Terraform Grafana

Languages

English
German
Russian

- Established system monitoring and error notifications for robust operations.
- Contributed to frontend development using atomic design principles and React.js

Software Engineer

Silicon Valley Insight

a 2018-2020

- remote
- Led diverse web and mobile application projects utilizing a wide range of technologies including React.js, Redux, TypeScript, Next.js, Node.js, Python, Flask, React Native and AWS.
- Managed backend projects and implemented robust software architecture solutions to optimize React Native applications.
- Conducted code reviews and mentored junior developers to enhance code quality and adherence to best practices.

IT Security Engineer

State Research Institute of Aviation Systems

= 2015-2018

- Moscow, Russian Federation
- Defined, implemented and maintained corporate security policies.
- Analyzed and advised on new security technologies and program conformance.
- Configured and setup software and workstations.
- Supported and trained end-users.

Backend Developer

Tunnll

= 2016-2017

remote

- Developed web applications for finding buses and buying tickets in small cities in Spain.
- Used programming capabilities in Python, Flask, Angular, PostgreSQL, Heroku and Docker.
- Conducted unit testing to deliver optimal browser functionality
- Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser, device and operating system compatibility.

Python / OpenERP Developer

Scientific and Technical Centre Atlas

2012-2014

- Moscow, Russian Federation
- Maintained the openERP framework and its existing modules.
- Developed new modules to automate the creation of financial documents according to Russian standards.
- Wrote specifications and documentation suitable for government level.
- · Performed e2e testing..

Web Developer

Freelance

= 2014-2020

- % remote
- Worked concurrently on several projects.
- Dynamic sites executed by PHP, Python and JavaScript.
- Worked as DevOps with Ansible and Jenkins.

Certifications

Usable Security,

University of Maryland, Issued Dec 2016

Software Security,

University of Maryland, Issued Nov 2017

Introduction to Cybersecurity
Tools & Cyber Attacks,
Coursera, Issued May 2022

<u>Network Security & Database</u> <u>Vulnerabilities,</u>

Coursera, Issued May 2022

Further projects

Christmas Trees

The project is an online Christmas tree shop. I have been involved in the project for 3 consecutive years.

I was engaged in a comparative analysis of the offer of a Christmas tree plantation, management of the import of Christmas trees, preparation for sales (purchase of necessary related products, rental of offices and warehouses, conclusion of contracts with delivery companies in Russia, organisation of delivery to branches), cash accounting and final profit calculation, development of an online store

Music Festival

The project is a four day open air electronic music festival.

I was engaged in the search for volunteers and management of their work at various venues of the festival, organisation of uninterrupted round-the-clock check and sale of tickets at the entrance to the festival.